## W. BROCK OVERCASH

4 Pine Tree Road • Salisbury, North Carolina 28144 • 704.754.0739 • brock.overcash@gatech.edu U.S. Citizen

### **OBJECTIVE**

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science degree candidate in the Denning Technology and Management Program acquiring a minor in Computing & Business with experience in working in production software environments on small teams and large teams. A self-starting candidate with intellectual curiosity and a desire to impact individuals pursuing a career in software design and management in an organization that promotes learning, exploration, and impactful production solutions.

# **EDUCATION**

# GEORGIA INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY, College of Computing

Atlanta, Georgia

**Bachelor of Science in Computer Science** 

May 2017

Threads: Devices and People

GPA: 4.0

- Minor in Computing and Business through the Denning Technology & Management Program
- Georgia Tech President's Scholarship Program Gold Scholar
- Barcelona Study Abroad Program (Summer 2014)

# **EXPERIENCE**

GOOGLE Seattle, Washington

Software Engineering Intern, DoubleClick Search

*May 2015 – August 2015* 

- Created same day validation for new DS feature with <1% error rate by extending internal data validation pipelines
- Improved internal validation dashboard filtering capabilities to support regex searching and segmenting of validation issues

RIGOR Atlanta, Georgia

Software Engineering Intern

August 2014 – March 2015

A software company focused on creating solutions for performance analytics monitoring, competition benchmarking, content monitoring and more.

- Generated an average of 8 new leads per day by creating website benchmarking tool Website Speed Ranker in Rigor Labs
- Reduced error count by 33% and modernized the styling and infrastructure of Rigor Labs tools to increase reliability
- Created an internal web service to interface Rigor production and labs apps with the backend infrastructure

SAMPLIFY MOBILE Atlanta, Georgia

Co-Project Lead and Developer

January 2014 – February 2014

The team of Georgia Tech students behind a mobile application for identifying songs sampled within other songs heard or played through a device. The application generated 8,000 downloads, 5,000 iOS interest postings, over 90,000 website hits, and multiple international article postings.

• Co-managed the project to integrate multiple new features that increased traffic to the application

#### LEADERSHIP

THETA XI FRATERNITY

Atlanta, Georgia

House Manager

April 2015 – Present

• Run the fraternity house in an efficient manner and organize work week to perform needed repairs on the house

Kitchen Manager

December 2014 – April 2015

• Facilitated meal plan transition that amounted to \$300 in savings per semester per member

Technology Chair

December 2013 – August 2015

• Manage email system, create and maintain website, and oversee chapter interactions with GT OIT

TEAM BUZZ Atlanta, Georgia

Co-Director of Development

January 2015 – Present

Responsible for vision planning for Team Buzz and seeking opportunities and engagement from Alumni and others

## SKILLS/INTERESTS

**Technical:** Java, Ruby on Rails, Python, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript

**Languages:** Spanish - Intermediate **Awards:** Theta Xi Rising Star Honoree

**Volunteer:** College of Computing Mentorship Program

**Interests:** Community service, travel, rock climbing, hiking, leather working